Curriculum Vitae

Name Felipe Tovar Falciano

Address ICRA - Department of Cosmology and Gravitation

Brazilian Center for Physics Research - CBPF

Dr. Xavier Sigaud street, 150 - Urca -

Rio de Janeiro, RJ – Brazil Phone: (+55 21) 2141-7374 ZIP 22290-180 email: ftovar@cbpf.br

Education

Ph.D. Brazilian Center for Physics Research, Rio De Janeiro, Brazil.

2004 - 2008 Title: "Non-Singular Scalar Field Universe Models"

Supervised by Dr. Nelson Pinto-Neto

Master Brazilian Center for Physics Research, Rio De Janeiro, Brazil.

2002 – 2004 Title: "Quantization of a FLRW Model with Two Fluids"

Supervised by Dr. Nelson Pinto-Neto

B.Sc. in Physics

1996 - 2001

Pontifical Catholic University of Rio de Janeiro

B.Ed. in Physics

1996 - 2001

Pontifical Catholic University of Rio de Janeiro

Professional Experience

Apr. 2009 – Present Brazilian Center for Physics Research, Rio De Janeiro, Brazil.

Assistant Research Professor

Apr. 2008 – Mar. 2009 Brazilian Center for Physics Research, Rio De Janeiro, Brazil.

Postdoctoral researcher

Sep. 2006 – Oct. 2007 IAP - Institut d'Astrophysique de Paris, Paris, France.

Sandwich Ph.D.

Supervised by Dr. Patrick Peter

Awards

2003 "bolsa aluno nota 10", FAPERJ - State funding agency

Special master scholarship for academic achievement

2000 "Outstanding International Student", University of Northern Colorado

award during undergraduate sandwich program.

1999 Academic Excellence, PUC-RJ - Pontifical Catholic University of Rio de Janeiro

award for academic achievement

1998 Academic Excellence, PUC-RJ - Pontifical Catholic University of Rio de Janeiro

award for academic achievement

Academic Excellence, PUC-RJ - Pontifical Catholic University of Rio de Janeiro

award for academic achievement

PhD and Master Supervision

PhD supervision: Cristofher Zuñiga Vargas(June 2012 – (prevision) 2016)

MSc supervision: Guilherme Nunes Bremm(Mar. 2011 – Apr. 2014), Róbinson José

Acosta Diaz(Mar. 2012 – Dec. 2014)

Undergraduate

Scientific Projects: Pedro da Silveira Ferreira(2012 - 2013), Lucas Pinheiro Cinelli(2012 -

2013), Pedro Kenzo de Alencar Ohi(2010 – 2011), Ricardo Rodrigues

Gomes(2010 – 2012), Carise Martins Angelo(2009 - 2010).

Research Highlights

Currently (December 2014) 20 records on INSPIRE, 17 of which in peer reviewed journals, and 3 in peer reviewed conference proceedings. An "h-factor" of 6.

Research interests

Cosmological perturbation theory, non-singular cosmological models, quantum cosmology, foundation of quantum mechanics.

Administrative Tasks

Member of the committee for Master and Ph.D student selection at CBPF (Nov. 2013, Mar. 2014, Nov. 2014)

Meeting Organizer:

Master examiner

- State University of Rio de Janeiro UERJ: P.C.M. Clemente (2013); M.A. Alcoforado (2012)
- Brazilian Center for Physics Research CBPF: C.R. de Bom (2013); F.A.G. Ferreira (2013); M.E.S. Pereira (2012); D.C.F. Celani (2011); J.N. Rua (2010); C.I.A.P.R. Paz (2009); E.H.S. Bittencourt (2009)

Ph.D. examiner

• Brazilian Center for Physics Research – CBPF: D.M. Pantoja (2014); S.D.P. Vitenti (2011); H.S.D. Montoya (2011); C.A. Hernaski (2011); M.P. Lima (2010); M.C.B. Carvalho (2010)